# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello guys, I am Wang Gang
# 本期视频我给大家分享
For today’s video, I am going to share the recipe of
# 凉拌绿豆芽
Bean Sprouts Salad
# 首先我们准备绿豆芽1000克
First, let’s prepare 1000g of mung bean sprouts
# 然后将豆芽的两头掐掉备用
Then pinch both ends off
# 豆芽的头尾都会有一股涩味
Both ends taste a bit astringent
# 去掉头尾的豆芽身价可以上升数倍
Bean sprouts without both ends have higher price
# 这一步的目的不仅去除了苦涩味而且还留下了豆芽的爽脆
This step removes the bitterness and preserves the crunchy texture of bean sprouts
# 1000克绿豆芽经过掐头去尾之后只剩下500克左右
After removing both ends, there is 500g of bean sprouts left
# 清理干净之后加入清水清洗干净
Add some water to rinse the bean sprouts
# 同学们处理这个菜的时候必须赋予足够的耐心
This dish requires patience
# 处理2斤绿豆芽大约需要40分钟左右
Preparing 2 jin (1kg) of bean sprouts takes around 40 min
# 清洗干净之后捞出控干水分
Drain out the water after rinsing it
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Next step, prepare the other ingredients
# 准备几个干辣椒清洗干净之后用剪刀剪成辣椒丝备用
Rinse a few dried chili peppers and cut them into thin strips with scissors
# 不能吃辣的同学可以不加
You can skip them if you don’t enjoy spiciness
# 准备大蒜30克剁碎备用
Mince 30g of garlic and set it aside
# 同学们大蒜应该剁得越细越好
The finer the better
# 这样在凉拌的时候才能够吸附在豆芽上面
so that it would stick to the bean sprouts easily
# 下一步开始调味
Then, let’s prepare the seasoning
# 碗中加入适量的白糖（约1克）
Add around 1g of white sugar into the bowl
# 加入蚝油2克
Then add 2g of oyster sauce
# 加入生抽酱油3克
Next is 3g of light soy sauce
# 加入少许白醋（约2克）
Add 2g of white vinegar
# 调好味之后搅拌均匀即可
Stir well after you finished adding the seasoning
# 下一步开始制作
Next step, start cooking
# 首先我们在锅中加入适量的清水
Firstly, add a suitable amount of water into the wok
# 开大火烧开之后加入食用盐2大勺（约5克）
Bring to a boil over high heat and add 2 spoonsful of salt (around 5g)
# 再加入适量的植物油
Then add some vegetable oil
# 然后将处理好的绿豆芽下锅焯水煮至断生（水开2秒即可）
Next, blanch the prepared bean sprouts until they are cooked (2 seconds in boiling water)
# 豆芽断生之后倒出控水
Drain the excess water after the bean sprouts are cooked
# 然后放入凉开水中透凉
Then soak them in cold water to cool
# 这一步的目的是让豆芽保持脆度
The purpose of this is to preserve the crunchiness of the bean sprouts
# 然后我们再次把锅烧热
Then, heat up the wok again
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的油烧至6成热
Add some oil and heat it until 180°C
# 油温6成热之后倒入装辣椒丝的碗中把辣椒炝香
Pour the hot oil into the bowl with the dried chilli peppers to bring out the aroma
# 然后再倒入蒜蓉汁中搅拌均匀
Then add it into the minced garlic sauce and mix well
# 豆芽透凉之后倒出沥干水分
Once the bean sprouts are cooled, drain out the water
# 最后将调好的料汁倒入盆中搅拌均匀即可装盘
Lastly, mix the sauce with the bean sprouts and it's ready to serve
# 一道口感爽脆的凉拌绿豆芽就制作完成
A plate of bean sprouts salad with crunchy texture is served
# 下面开始技术总结
Below is the technical summary for today’s video:
第一，去除豆芽头尾的目的是减少涩味，嫌麻烦的同学可以忽略
First, removing both ends of bean sprouts is to reduce the astringent taste, you can ignore this if you think it’s too troublesome.
第二，豆芽下锅焯水不能煮太久否则不脆
Secondly, don’t blanch the bean sprouts for too long or they will lose the crunchiness.
第三，焯水的时候可以多放一下盐，后期凉拌的时候可以不加盐
Thirdly, you can add more salt when blanching them, this way you don’t need to add salt in the sauce.
第四，此菜原料虽成本不高，但极具考验每一位美食家的耐心
Fourthly, the cost for this dish isn’t high, but it requires a lot of patience.
凉拌豆芽的技术总结完毕
This is it for the technical summary.